by now most people have heard about the
Manulife one mortgage the checking
account that allows you to combine your
debt your savings in your income into
one convenient account we also know that
by doing this we have the potential to
save thousands of dollars in interest
and be debt-free years earlier the
question is how does it work meet James
his wife Monica and of course their
daughter Erica they like the idea of
saving money but don't really understand
how the Manulife one mortgage works or
if it's right for them the reason that
Manulife one is so much more efficient
it's the way in which interest is
charged let's use these measuring cups
to examine how the accounts work we have
Manulife 1 and then we also have
traditional banking a mortgage and a
checking account separately the empty
cups represent the total amount of debt
that they owe like a hole that needs to
be filled in if we look at a typical
month at some point our income is placed
into our accounts from that the mortgage
payment is due immediately you can see
the difference in the amount of debt
that you pay interest on with
traditional banking interest is based on
a monthly balance with Manulife 1
interest is accumulated daily so the
more you keep in the account the less
interest you have to pay then over the
course of the month we buy groceries pay
bills get gas buy gifts and even spend a
little on ourselves then before you know
it your income is placed back into your
account and the whole cycle of saving
starts again by keeping your income in a
separate account it does almost nothing
to help save you or earn you money so
for James and Monica by switching to
manual life one it looks like they could
save up to twenty four thousand dollars
in interest and be debt-free and almost
half the amount of time if you'd like to
be debt-free sooner and financially free
to live life your way give us a call we
would be happy to show you the way
Pattin financial services success
travels at the speed of implementation
you